In the previous quiz,
في الاختبار السابق،
you were introduced to four data sets of X,
تعرَّفتم على أربع مجموعات للبيانات من الأزواج X
Y pairs and you found that they all share the same mean and standard deviation.
وY، ووجدتم أنها جميعًا تتشارك نفس العدد المتوسط والانحراف المعياري.
So you might think that the points are very similar to one another.
إذًا ربما تعتقدون أن النقاط شديدة التطابق مع بعضها البعض.
It turns out, the mean,
يتضح لنا أن العدد المتوسط
the variance, the correlation,
والمتفاوت والارتباط
and the line of best fit are all exactly the same for these four data sets.
وخط الملاءمة الأفضل هي جميعًا متطابقة تمامًا في هذه المجموعات الأربع للبيانات.
But how similar are these data sets really?
لكن ما مدى التشابه بين مجموعات البيانات هذه فعليًا؟
It turns out, not very.
اتضح أن التشابه ليس شديدًا؛
This is something called Anscombe's quartet and
هذا شيء يُسمى رباعية Anscombe
demonstrates how important it is to always plot your data.
ويظهِر مدى أهمية أن ترسموا مخططات لبياناتكم دائمًا.
It is important that you pick out visual patterns, trends,
من المهم أن تختاروا قوالب مرئية واتجاهات
and outliers during your analysis,
وقيم خارجية أثناء تحليلكم،
as relying on only summary statistics can be misleading.
حيث أن الاعتماد على الإحصائيات الملخصة وحدها قد يكون مضللًا.
Below is a link to Alberto Cairo's DataSaurus which
تجدون أدناه رابطًا إلى عملاق البيانات الخاص بألبيرتو كايرو،
shows another example which is even crazier than this example.
والذي يعرض مقالًا آخر أكثر جنونًا من هذا المثال،
He uses the same idea but he finds a star,
حيث يستخدم نفس الفكرة لكنه يعثر على نجمة
a circle, and a data source that all share the same summary statistic.
ودائرة ومصدر بيانات تتشارك جميعًا نفس الإحصائية الملخصة.